[What Ito truly sought was the ties with
other people that he had severed...]
[The Shinsengumi Crisis Arc comes to its conclusion!]
(銀時)くっ…｡
(河上)手足が ちぎれると
言ったはずでござる！
I told you that your arms
and legs will rip off.
誰が あんな連中
助けに行きてぇかよ…｡
Who'd want to go and save
their sorry asses?
止まらねえんだよ…｡
体が 言うことを聞かねえ｡
I can't stop. My body won't listen to me.
勝手に前に引き寄せられる…｡
It's being pulled forward...Strings are pulling
me from the front and the back.
前からも 後ろからも
糸が絡まって…➡
引っ張ってきやがる！
It annoys me to no end...
うっとうしくて しかたねえ！
《河上:鉄の強度を誇る弦が…!?》
These strings are as strong
as steel, but still...
手足の１本や ２本くれてやらぁ！
You can have an arm and a leg or two.
…だが 肉は切れても
この糸… 腐れ縁！
Even if these strings can cut flesh...
I'd like to see them try to sever
an obnoxious bond!
切れるもんなら 切ってみやがれ!!
ふっ…｡
(土方)伏せろ！
Get down!
♪♪～
うお～っ!!
(伊東)ｺﾞﾎｯ…｡
Ito!
Sensei!
(近藤)先生!!
伊東…!?
(伊東)ｺﾞﾎｯ…｡
伊東!!
Ito!
うわっ！
うおらぁ!!
["It's All About the Beat and Timing"]
(新八)銀さん!!
Gin-san!
Bansai-sama... In front!
(ﾊﾟｲﾛｯﾄ)万斉様！
前が…！
(河上)ﾌﾝｯ…!!
白夜叉！ ｷｻﾏは 何がために戦う！
何がために 命をかける！
White Knight! What is it you fight for?
What is it you risk your life for?!
(河上)もはや
侍の世界の崩壊は免れん！
The destruction of the samurai's
world is already inevitable.
晋助が手を下さずとも
いずれ この国は腐り落ちる｡
Even if Shinsuke does not soil his
hands, this country will rot away!
主が ひとり
あがいたところで止まりはせん！
Your struggles alone will not stop it!
(河上)この国に
護る価値など もはやない｡
There's no longer anything worth
saving of this country!
天人に食い尽くされ
醜く腐る国に➡
It's the samurai's duty to graciously give
this rotting country which has been completely
ravaged by the Amanto it's final rites!
潔く 引導を
渡してやるが侍の役目！
この国は 腹を切らねばならん!!
This country must slit its belly!
死にてぇなら ひとりで
練炭自殺でも何でもしやがれ！
If you want to die, then go ahead
and kill yourself with the coals!
[Note: Coal briquettes are often used for
suicide by carbon monoxide poisoning.]
坂田 銀時… ｷｻﾏは亡霊でござる｡
Gintoki Sakata...you are a ghost.
You once tried to protect this country
along with Shinsuke and the others.
(河上)かつて 侍の国を護ろうと
晋助らとともに戦った思い…｡
それを捨てられず 妄執し
とらわれる… 生きた亡霊だ！
You are obsessed and unable to
let go. You are a living ghost.
主の護るべきものなど
もう ありはしない！
There is no longer anything
for you to protect!
亡霊は 帰るべきところへ帰れ!!
Ghosts should go back
where they belong.
ﾚｸｲｴﾑを くれてやるでござる｡
I'll play you a requiem!
あっ… 弦が…!?
The strings...!
おい にいちゃん｡
Hey, bud!
ﾍｯﾄﾞﾎﾝ取れ！ この野郎！
Take off those headphones, dammit!
いつの間に拙者の弦を…
何してる 撃て！
When did he grab my strings?
What're your waiting for? Fire!
耳の穴 かっぽじって よ～く聞け｡
Clean out your ears and listen up!
ｵﾚぁ 安い国なんぞのために
戦ったことは 一度たりともねえ！
I've never once fought for the
sake of this cheap country.
国が滅ぼうが 侍が滅ぼうが➡
I couldn't care less...
if the country or samurai
fell. I have always...
どうでもいいんだよ！
ｵﾚぁ 昔っから!!
Then, and now...
今も昔も
ｵﾚの護るもんは 何ひとつ…！
What I protect...
♪♪～
has never changed!
変わっちゃいねえ！
うお～っ！
♪♪～
Bansai-sama!
(浪士)万斉様…！
(伊東)何をしている!?
What're you doing?
Get your heads out of your asses!
(伊東)ﾎﾞﾔﾎﾞﾔするな！
副長… 指揮を！
Vice-Chief...
...your orders...
♪♪～
総員に告ぐ！
敵の大将は討ち取った！
This is to all of you! I've taken their leader's head!
もはや敵は
統率を失った烏合の衆！
The enemy is nothing more
than a flock of lost sheep!
一気に たたみかけろぉ！
Finish them off all at once!
(近藤)てやぁ…！
♪♪～
Tsk, retreat!
(浪士)ﾁｯ… 引けぇ！
(土方)逃がすな！ 討ち取れぇ！
Don't let them get away! Kill them all!
(足音)
なんで あんなことを…｡
Why...why did you do that?
裏切りなんてした あなたが➡
You committed treason.
Why did you protect us?
なんで ﾎﾞｸらを
かばったりなんかしたんですか？
ｷﾐたちは 真選組ではないな…｡
You're...not Shinsengumi...
だが 彼らと 言葉ではいいがたい
糸で繋がっているようだ｡
but you seem to be tied to them in
a way that words cannot describe.
友情とも違う 敵とも違う…｡
You're neither friends,
nor are you enemies.
ただの腐れ縁です｡
...we're obnoxious bonds.
Hmph, I suppose there
are ties like that...
ﾌﾌ… そんな形の糸もあるのだな｡
知らなかった…
いや 知ろうとしなかっただけか｡
I didn't know. Or rather, I
didn't try to understand.
人と繋がりたいと願いながら
自ら人との糸を断ち切ってきた｡
Despite hoping to create ties with people,
I severed them on my side.
ちっぽけな自尊心を護るために➡
I lost sight of what I really wanted because
I tried to protect a tiny bit of pride.
本当に欲しかったものさえ
見失ってしまうとは…｡
ようやく見つけた大切な絆さえ
自ら壊してしまうとは…｡
Even when I finally found the ties
that were important to me,
I destroyed them on my side.
(伊東)なぜ… なぜ いつだって➡
Why...
Why is it always too late when
you finally realize that?
気づいたときには遅いんだ｡
なぜ ともに戦いたいのに
立ち上がれない｡
Why is that I want to fight with everyone
but I can't even stand?
なぜ 剣を握りたいのに腕がない｡
Why is that I want to wield my
sword, but I have no arm?
なぜ ようやく気づいたのに
ﾎﾞｸは死んでいく…｡
Why is it that...I finally truly realized
that...but I'm going to die...?
I don't want to die. If I die, I'll be
alone...no ties would reach me...
死にたくない… 死ねば１人だ｡
どんな糸さえ届かない！
もう １人は…｡
I don't want to be alone anymore...
(原田)ｿｲﾂを…
こちらに渡してもらえるか｡
We'd like you to...
hand him over to us.
お願いです｡ この人はもう…｡
...Please. He's gone through enough.
万事屋… 今回は
お前らには世話になった｡
Odd Jobs... We owe you
for your help this time.
But we cannot heed your request.
だが その頼みだけはきけない｡
How many people do you think
lost their lives because of him?
ｿｲﾂのために 何人が
犠牲になったと思っている？
裏切り者は ｵﾚたちで
処分しなきゃならねえ｡
We must deal with the traitor ourselves.
助けてもらったんです それに…！
He saved us! And he...
近藤さん！
連れていけ｡
Kondo-san!
Take him.
なんで!?
Why?!
Kondo-san, why...?
近藤さん どうして!?
Kondo-san...
近藤さん！
That's right...he'd die anyway
even if they left him alone.
そうさ… ほっといたって
ﾔﾂは もう死ぬ｡
…だからこそ｡
That's exactly why...
That's exactly why they must kill him.
だからこそ 斬らなきゃならねえ｡
Get up...Ito.
(土方)立て 伊東｡
決着 つけようじゃねえか｡
What do you say we settle this?
They...don't want him to die
a filthy traitor's death.
ｱｲﾂら…
ﾔﾂを薄汚い 裏切り者のまんま…｡
死なせたくねえんだよ｡
They want him to end his
life...as a samurai...
最後は 武士として…｡
仲間として➡
...and a fellow comrade.
That's the death he deserves.
ﾔﾂを 死なせてやりてぇんだよ｡
♪♪～
土方～!!
Hijikata!
Ito!
伊東～！
(２人)うお～！
♪♪～
…が とう…｡
...ank...you...
あり… がとう…｡
Thank...you...
♪♪～
♪♪(三味線)
(高杉)そうかい 伊東は死に
真選組が生き残ったか…｡
I see. Ito died and the
Shinsengumi survived.
So the Bakufu is unexpectedly
alive and well.
存外… まだまだ幕府も
丈夫じゃねえか｡
いや… 伊東が もろかったのか？
No, perhaps Ito was weak...or...
それとも？
Was it you who was weak, Bansai?
万斉 お前が弱かったのか？
元々 今回の仕事は➡
The original intent of this job
真選組の目を 幕府中央から
引き離すのが目的｡
was to draw away the Shinsengumi's
attention from the Bakufu bigwigs.
春雨が 無事 密航し➡
If the Harusame successfully
made their secret voyage
and a secret agreement was reached with the Bakufu
bigwigs, there's no need for a battle.
中央との密約が 成ったとなれば
戦闘の必要もなし｡
牽制の意は 果たしたでござる｡
We would have succeeded
in warding them off.
ｵﾚは 真選組を潰すつもりで
行けと言ったはずだ｡
I thought I told you to handle this with
the intent of crushing the Shinsengumi.
(河上)何事にも
重要なのは ﾉﾘとﾘｽﾞﾑでござる｡
As in all things, it's all about
the beat and the timing.
これを欠けば何事もうまくいかぬ｡
Without both, nothing will go well.
If I can't get into it, I back out
immediately. That's how I do things.
のれぬとあれば
即座に引くが拙者のやり方｡
万斉 ｵﾚの歌にはのれねえか？
Bansai.
You can't get attuned my song?
白夜叉が ｵﾚの護るものは
今も昔も何ひとつ変わらんと｡
The White Knight said, "What
I protect has never changed."
晋助 何かわかるか？
Shinsuke...any idea what
he was talking about?
It made me feel like asking
him until I find out.
(河上)最後まで聞きたく
なってしまったでござるよ｡
♪♪～
ﾔﾂらの歌に聞き惚れた｡
拙者の負けでござる｡
I've fallen in love with
their song. I've lost.
♪♪(三味線)
(読経)
《山崎:ﾔﾊﾞｲ… ﾔﾊﾞｲ！
...This is bad...
Really bad. They totally think I'm dead.
完全に
死んだことになってるよ ｵﾚ！
ま まさか
もう葬式まで開いてるとは…｡
I never dreamed they would
hold a funeral so soon.
完全に出遅れた｡
出るﾀｲﾐﾝｸﾞを逸した》
I'm totally too late. I blew the timing.
((河上:気が変わったでござる｡
...I've changed my mind.
主の歌 も少し聞きたくなった｡
I want to hear...a bit more of your song.
Live on, I look forward to the day when
you'll let me here the rest of it.
生き延びて
その続き聞かせてくれる日を➡
楽しみにしているでござる))
And so that's how it went.
《などという やりとりがあり➡
ｵﾚが 奇跡的に生存していたなんて
誰も思っていまい｡
No one expected that I would
miraculously still be alive.
ﾏｽﾞｲぞ… 敵に
情けをかけられて助かったうえ➡
This is bad.
Not only was I spared because
of the enemy's compassion,
今の今まで入院し
連絡もつかなんだことがﾊﾞﾚれば…｡
but if they found out I spent all this time
in the hospital without contacting them...
しかも このﾀｲﾐﾝｸﾞ…》
And the timing couldn't be worse.
((すみません
やっぱ生きてました！))
"Sorry, I'm alive, after all."
《なんつって出てったら
間違いなく粛正される｡
If I showed up like that, they'd
discipline me...for sure.
ﾔﾊﾞｲよ どうしよう！
死んじゃおっかな｡
I'm in big trouble. What'll I do?!
Maybe I should die. At this point, things
would be easier if I were dead.
もうこれ
死んだほうが楽じゃねえ？》
(松平)ﾊﾞｶﾔﾛｳ！ 年寄りより
先にいっちまいやがってぇ…｡
You fool! Leaving this life before
an old man! You....you...you...!
《山崎:やめて！
それ以上 盛り上がらないで！
Stop it! Don't make it any worse!
どんどん出づらくなる！》
You're making it harder and
harder for me to show myself.
ｵﾚはなぁ ｵﾒｴのことを
本当の息子のように思って ｳｯ…｡
You know I...thought of
you...like a real son...
《山崎:でも
とっつあん そんなにｵﾚのこと…》
I didn't know...
...Pops...that you thought
so highly of me...
(松平)ﾌﾟｰ助！
ｵﾚを置いていかないでくれ！
Pusuke! Don't leave me behind!
《なぜに 犬とｾｯﾄ！
Why am I alongside a dog?!
ｾｯﾄっつうかこれ 完全に
犬が主役の葬式じゃねえか！
Or rather...this funeral is
totally about the dog!
It's like, "we may as well include
Yamazaki while we're at it!"
犬のついでに 山崎も
弔っとくか的な葬式じゃねえか！
いくら地味だからって
それは ねえだろ～っ！
Regardless of how unremarkable
I may have been, this is too cruel!
つうか 何で
仏前に ﾆﾛを供えてあんだよ！
Why is there a can of Nilo
there as an offering?!
[Note: Parody of Milo, the Nestle chocolate drink.]
別に好きでもなんでもねえよ！
あ… おい坊主！ 何 ｵﾚの
ﾆﾛちびりちびり飲んでんだよ！
Hey Priest! Why're you
sipping on my Nilo?!
別に好きでもないけど
やめろ！ 腹立つ》
Not that I really cared for it
or anything, but cut it out!
You're making me angry.
Hey! Turn off that cell phone.
《山崎:おい ｹｰﾀｲ切れ！》
Huh? I'm at the funeral for
Boss Matsudaira's dog.
あっ？ 今
松平のとっつぁんの犬の葬式｡
《山崎:ｵﾚの葬式と言え！》
Tell them it's my funeral.
いてて… 何か足しびれたな｡
Oww...
My leg fell asleep.
《山崎:ﾃﾒｴは ｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣をしまえ！
Put away the JUMP, dammit.
お前ら
人の命をなんだと思ってるんだ！
Doesn't a human life mean
anything to you?
ﾋﾄﾞｲ！ まるで
規律を失ったﾁﾝﾋﾟﾗ集団だ｡
How could they! They're like an
undisciplined gang of hoodlums.
副長は
副長はまだ戻らないのか？》
The Vice-Chief...isn't the
Vice-Chief back yet?
What's with this? Haven't they
lifted Vice-Chief's punishment?
なんだよ 副長 謹慎処分
解けたんじゃねえのかよ？
副長の活躍がなければ
真選組は 今頃潰れてたぜ｡
Without his leadership, the Shinsengumi
wouldn't exist today.
Seems he feels personally
responsible this time.
どうにも今回の件
責任感じちゃってるみたいだよ｡
自分から
謹慎処分の延期申し出たって｡
I heard he personally asked for
the suspension to be extended.
(隊士)そういや 前も
様子 変だったしな｡
Come to think of it, he acted
strangely back then too.
(隊士)まさか 真選組に➡
You think he won't come back
to the Shinsengumi?
戻ってこねえなんてことは
ねえよな？
After what happened,
(隊士)あんなことがあったし➡
we may not be able to return to the
Shinsengumi we were before.
もう ｵﾚたち 以前の真選組に
戻れねえかもしれねぇな｡
Thank you for waiting.
(店員)お待たせしました！
I visited every temple
and shrine in the city
(土方)あらゆる神社仏閣を訪ね➡
あらゆるまじない念仏を
唱えてもらってきたが➡
and had them do every incantation
and prayer they knew.
But in the end, this never left my side.
ついに ｺｲﾂが
体から離れることはなかった｡
Seems this thing's curse...is deeply
ingrained in my very being.
どうにも ｺｲﾂの呪い… ｵﾚの体
奥深くまで くい込んでるようだ｡
No telling when this will
consume me again.
また いつ 何どき ｺｲﾂに
くわれちまうか わからねえ｡
それじゃ 真選組 復帰は…｡
Does that mean you won't return
to the Shinsengumi?
(神楽)転職を考えたほうが
よさそうあるな｡
You should think about changing jobs.
Maybe you should join Animate.
[Note: Animate is a chain that sells
everything related to animation.]
ｱﾆﾒｲﾄにでも就職するあるか？
結構なことじゃねえの｡
Sounds good to me.
体から離れねえ妖刀…
まさしく 剣身一体ってわけだ｡
A demonic sword that never
leaves your side.
You are truly one with your sword.
It's the perfect sword for you.
ﾃﾒｴに おあつらえの剣じゃねえか｡
((ｱﾝﾀは真選組の魂だ｡
ｵﾚたちはそれを護る剣なんだよ))
You are the soul of the Shinsengumi.
We are the sword that protects you.
軽く言ってくれるぜ｡
You say that so casually.
世話になったな｡
土方さん どこに行くんですか？
Thanks for you help.
Hijikata-san, where are you going?
Isn't it obvious?
(土方)決まってんだろ｡
ｵﾚの体は とうの昔に
霊やら たたりやらで 定員ｵｰﾊﾞｰさ｡
My body has more angry spirits and curses
on it than it can accommodate.
It's full of all the people I've stepped
over and the enmity of my comrades.
今まで 踏み越えてきた
敵や仲間たちの怨念でな｡
今さら 呪いのひとつやふたつ
増えたところで 何も変わらねえ｡
What's another curse or two gonna do?
I don't intend to look back
no matter who dies.
誰が 死のうが
振り返るつもりもねえ｡
I intend to shoulder every one
of them and move forward...
(土方)全部 背負って
前に進むだけだ｡
so they won't laugh at me in Hell.
地獄でﾔﾂらに笑われねえようにな｡
いい天気ですね｡
...Nice weather.
(神楽)あっ！
ｷﾞｬﾗ もらうの 忘れたある｡
Oh.
We forgot to collect our fee.
いいんだよ｡
Forget it.
It's better to collect a little at a
time rather than all at once.
一気にもらうより 一生
ﾁﾋﾞﾁﾋﾞ たかったほうが 得だろ｡
ｱﾊﾊ！ でも 大丈夫ですかね？
ちゃんと働いていけるかな？
Do you think he'll be okay, though?
Will he be able to continue working?
大丈夫さ｡
He'll be fine.
もう 心配いらねえよ｡
We don't have to worry any more.
(松平)え～い あらよっと！
Oh yeah, here we go!
(松平の歌声)
They don't give a shit!
What do they think a funeral is?!
《ふざけやがって！ 人の葬式を
なんだと思ってやがんだ｡
I'll show all of you!
You all should be punished!
目にもの 見せてやる！
ﾊﾞﾁあたりどもが!!
I'll scare the hell out of all of you and...
ﾃﾒｴら 全員
恐怖のどん底に突き落として…》
うわ～っ!!
どわっ！
ぐわっ！
ｷﾞｬｰｯ!! 山崎が化けて出た！
(土方)局中法度 12条｡
Yamazaki returned from the dead!
Rule No. 22.
｢ﾏｶﾞｼﾞﾝ｣以外の漫画
局内で読むことなかれ｡
No reading of manga, except for MAGAZINE,
allowed in the headquarters.
[Note: Refers to "Weekly Shonen MAGAZINE,
a rival of Shonen JUMP.]
Rule No. 17.
局中法度 17条｡
Turn off cell phones during meetings
and important ceremonies.
会議 および 重要な式典の際は
ｹｰﾀｲの電源を切るべし｡
Rule No. 45.
局中法度 45条｡ 死して なお
化けて出ることなかれ｡
Do not die and return from the dead.
Samurai should rest in peace
with good grace.
武士たる者
潔く 成仏すべし｡
ﾃﾒｴら 全員
士道不覚悟で 切腹だ！
The entire lot of you are breaking the
Bushido principles! Slit your bellies!
(隊士)副長…｡
Vice-Chief...
副長!!
ｲﾃｯ！ うっ！ くさっ!!
Vice-Chief!
Ouch.
Stop it.
(隊士)やった！
副長が戻ってきた!!
Hooray! The Vice-Chief came back!
What're you guys talking about?
な… 何 言って…！
ﾃﾒｴ!! 切腹だって…｡
I said you all have to slit your bellies!
(隊士)あぁ しますとも！
何度でも かっさばきますとも!!
Oh, we will. We'll do it as
many times as you want.
《ﾄｼ… ｵﾒｴは ｵﾚを
真選組の魂なんて言ったがよ➡
Toshi... You said I was the
soul of the Shinsengumi.
ｺｲﾂらにとっちゃ ｵﾒｴも
かけがえのない魂なんだよ｡
But to these guys, you're also an
irreplaceable part of that soul.
Good to have you back...Toshi.
よく帰ってきてくれたな ﾄｼ》
(着信ﾒﾛﾃﾞｨｰ)
(土方)はい もしもし｡
土方でござる｡
Hello. Hijikata speaking de gozaru.
[Preview]
Strikers are beasts that
live to score goals.
What awaits at the end of the road
for those who seek to score?
Kick it in, Amarao!
["Love Is Often
Played Out In Sudden Death"]
[Daisaku Amarao, star player of FC Oedo hires
Gin-san and his friends to play soccer.]
[Note: FC is short for Football Club.]
[Next week's "GinTama" has a lot of balls!
Pretty good, eh? Get it?]
[Note: Play on the "tama" in "GinTama",
which literally means silver balls.]